<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" 
      xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" 
      xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" 
      xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" 
      version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>Tina Rozsos</title>
<link>https://tinarozsos.github.io/news.html</link>
<atom:link href="https://tinarozsos.github.io/news.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<description>Personal website of Tina Rozsos</description>
<generator>quarto-1.8.24</generator>
<lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 May 2026 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<item>
  <title>New website is live!</title>
  <link>https://tinarozsos.github.io/news/250917_new_website.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p>I lauched a new version of my website!</p>
<p>This is the new home page: <img src="https://tinarozsos.github.io/assets/img/250917_home.jpg" class="img-fluid" alt="Image of the home page featuring rainbow-colored cards to subpages of the website"></p>
<section id="quarto" class="level1">
<h1>Quarto</h1>
<p>Previously run on Beautiful Jekyll and Rmarkdown, I have now transitioned to <a href="https://quarto.org/">Quarto</a>. The website it still published via GitHub Pages, but now the <a href="https://github.com/tinarozsos/tinarozsos.github.io">source code</a> is cleaner, with only the QMD files, SCSS stylesheet, and other assets in the repo. The website is now also more mobile-friendly, and allows more features of Quarto.</p>
</section>
<section id="visual-identity" class="level1">
<h1>Visual identity</h1>
<p>I got bored of the previous design, and wanted something more whimsical. I also thought it would be good to highlight more of my work, especially my R projects.</p>
<p>Now the landing page features a set of cards directing to different parts of the website. I introduced new pages to share news and updates from my work, and a portfolio of my R projects. These pages will slowly be populated with content. The cards themselves are illustrated with some of my own R-based generative art – all code is available on <a href="https://github.com/tinarozsos/art">GitHub</a>.</p>
<p>I shifted the colour scheme to a colorful pastel palette, chose a new font set (Quicksand and Inter), and made use of icons for a bit of extra flair. The header and footer color matches my newly painted walls – gotta keep the visual identity consistent online and offline! (or maybe I just really like the color)</p>
<p>Anyway, so far I’m enjoying the new design, and there is certainly more to come.</p>
</section>
<section id="credits" class="level1">
<h1>Credits</h1>
<p>In addition to heavily relying on the <a href="https://quarto.org/docs/websites/">Quarto website documentation</a>, the home page card setup was inspired by the websites of <a href="https://ellakaye.co.uk/">Ella Kaye</a> and <a href="https://djnavarro.net/">Danielle Navarro</a>. And since my HTML and CSS skills are not quite aligned with the level of customisation I desire, chunks of the SCSS file and some of the HTML bits in the QMD files are the results of extensive back-and-forth chats with ChatGPT.</p>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <guid>https://tinarozsos.github.io/news/250917_new_website.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sat, 09 May 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://tinarozsos.github.io/assets/img/250917_home.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
