<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" 
      xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" 
      xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" 
      xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" 
      version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>Tina Rozsos</title>
<link>https://tinarozsos.github.io/r.html</link>
<atom:link href="https://tinarozsos.github.io/r.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<description>Personal website of Tina Rozsos</description>
<generator>quarto-1.8.27</generator>
<lastBuildDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 13:01:45 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<item>
  <title>Generative(/procedural) art with R</title>
  <link>https://tinarozsos.github.io/r/art.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p>I played around with using {ggplot2} and {ambient} to make art in R. I relied heavily on tutorials by {Danielle Navarro](https://blog.djnavarro.net/) and others, and enjoyet setting up various systems and working out how various tweaks to the underlying code affected the output.</p>
<p>I put together a sort-of gallery with links to the source code of each image <a href="https://tinarozsos.github.io/art/">here</a>.</p>



 ]]></description>
  <guid>https://tinarozsos.github.io/r/art.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 13:01:45 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>PhD documentation with R and Quarto</title>
  <link>https://tinarozsos.github.io/r/phd-template.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p>Based on the site I use to keep track of the knowledge and documentation I accumulate during my ongoing PhD, I prepared a ready-to-use template.</p>
<p>Have a look at the example site generated by the template <a href="https://tinarozsos.github.io/phd-template/">here</a>.</p>
<iframe src="https://tinarozsos.github.io/phd-template/" width="100%" height="400" style="border:2px solid #444; border-radius:6px;">
</iframe>
<p>The <a href="https://github.com/tinarozsos/phd-template">GitHub repository</a> contains the template and documentation on how to modify all aspects of the site.</p>



 ]]></description>
  <guid>https://tinarozsos.github.io/r/phd-template.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 13:01:45 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Shiny app to learn Dutch</title>
  <link>https://tinarozsos.github.io/r/nt2.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p>While taking Dutch courses, I found it easy to practice in class and do the assigned homework in preparation, but I often found myself unmotivated to effectively work on my vocabulary outside of class and assignments.</p>
<p>To make practice more fun for myself, I took the PDF vocabulary lists that came with our textbook, scraped the contents into CSV files, and built an interactive Shiny app. After selecting which units I want to cover and what kind of exercise to see (translating to Dutch, to English, idioms, phrases, or irregular verbs), I get a randomly generated exercise lists, and can input my answers into a textbox before looking at the solutions.</p>
<p>The app looks rather ugly, but I could’t justify spending more time on making it look nicer. I had to actually go practice the vocabulary after all. :)</p>
<p>The app is available on <a href="https://tina-r.shinyapps.io/VU-NT2/">shinyapps.io</a>. As for proof that it works: after using the app to spend many train rides practicing on my phone instead of scrolling through social media, I had no problems passing the exams at the end of the course.</p>



 ]]></description>
  <guid>https://tinarozsos.github.io/r/nt2.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 13:01:45 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Shiny-based memory game</title>
  <link>https://tinarozsos.github.io/r/taskmaster-game.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p>One of my friends really likes the UK TV show <em>Taskmaster</em>, and so do I. So when her birthday was coming up, I made her a fun game based on <em>Taskmaster</em> quotes in the best way I could think of: a Shiny app!</p>
<p>The game design is very simple. There are 8 pairs of cards, face down in a grid. The player must find all matching pairs by flipping over two cards at a time. But instead of having pairs of identical images, the pairs are a quote, item, or action, and the person most closely associated with it.</p>
<p>While it’s just about the simplest game imaginable in real life, implementing it as a Shiny app came with various challenges to get all mechanisms right. At the same time, both the server logic and the <em>Taskmaster</em>-style theming proved to be great opportunities for some experimentation with Positron Assistant.</p>
<p>In addition, I could practice my web scraping skills by extracting quotes from the <a href="https://taskmaster.fandom.com/wiki/Taskmaster_Wiki">Taskmaster Wiki</a> and had fun choosing my favorite <a href="https://www.instagram.com/taskmasternocontext/">out-of-context quotes</a>. This was also my first time using Posit Connect Cloud instead of shinyapps.io, and I was very pleased with the experience.</p>
<p>Want to play the game? Try it <a href="https://tina-r-happy-birthday-fleur.share.connect.posit.cloud/">here</a>!</p>



 ]]></description>
  <guid>https://tinarozsos.github.io/r/taskmaster-game.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 13:01:45 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://tinarozsos.github.io/assets/img/taskmaster-game.png" medium="image" type="image/png" height="72" width="144"/>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
